## Vishnu Suresh

Date of birth: 26/02/1991 | Nationality: Indian | Gender: Male | Phone number: (+966) 571987880 (Home) |

**Email address:** vishnuskp@gmail.com | **LinkedIn:** https://www.linkedin.com/in/vishnu-suresh-41729159/ |

Address: Riyadh, Saudi Arabia (Home)

#### ABOUT ME

I have over 12 years of experience in IT development, Project Management, Business Analysis and Support as a professional. I have a wide range of expertise working with various technologies with teams all around the world, having worked in Saudi Arabia and India. I'm seeking a fresh challenge.

#### WORK EXPERIENCE

03/10/2022 Saudi Arabia

### **BUSINESS ANALYST IT J&T EXPRESS**

- Product Requirements Analysis and Integration.
- Scope and Execution of Project.
- Gathering and analyzing product requirements from stakeholders.
- Preparing detailed documentation for implementation and integration.
- Transforming Business needs to technical specifications.
- Managing API integration with client's systems and Webhook configuration.
- · Creating Reports, Dashboards and Data Analysis.
- Sandbox Testing with Postman for APIs and Webhook in JSON script.
- Supporting and managing internal company applications.
- Analyzing operational needs and reconciling needs of different teams.
- Conducting UAT Testing and Production for Modules.
- Resolving problems or discrepancies with orders.
- Managing and leading team members.
- Communicating with clients about incident progress and changes.
- Escalating service or project issues.
- Working with other departments to synchronize operational functionality.
- Integration assistance and plugin managing for E-Commerce Platforms and Logistics.

02/10/2018 - 02/10/2020 Saudi Arabia

#### **BUSINESS ANALYST SAYYAR E-COMMERCE**

- Organized startup firm's E-Commerce Operations.
- Conducted market analysis and Data Visualization.
- Managed internal and external stakeholders.
- Work closely with Development teams.
- Provided L3 support for the customer care team.
- Managed teams and coordinated Supply Chain and Logistics.
- Developed and maintained a comprehensive knowledge base for effective issue resolution.
- Troubleshooted and identified potential solutions for service desk problems.
- Assisted solutions teams in improving solutions.
- Analyzed performance of support activities and recommended improvements.
- Act as second/third line of support for complex technical issues.
- Coordinated with the Digital Marketing team.
- Writing complex gueries in SQL and Access.
- Data Analysis using Power BI, Tableau, Excel.
- · Working with ETL Methodologies.
- Creating User Stories and working in Agile Methodologies.

12/07/2014 - 12/10/2018 Saudi Arabia

## **IT ENGINEER SOMATCO**

- IT Support Team Role Overview
- Leading and managing IT Support Team's operations.
- Conducting detailed analysis and reporting based on company data.

- Managing SQL and Microsoft Access Database.
- Handling First Level Support of Service Requests professionally and timely.
- Assisting in creating procedural and training materials.
- Managing IT budget allocation.
- Implementing remote access solutions.
- Maintaining ticket records and improving solutions.
- Developing new software application modules.
- Creating Crystal Report reports.
- Remote Desktop Support.
- Server Management.
- Technical Support for Hardware and Software.
- Content management in website and internal application.

10/07/2012 - 02/11/2014 India

#### **SYSTEM ANALYST CERPS TECHNOLOGY**

- Creating modules for ASP.NET projects.
- Supporting and error-fixing in ASP.NET applications.
- Managing the product development lifecycle from ideation to launch.
- Analyzing client requirements and submitting reports to the technical team.
- Collaborating with cross-functional teams to prioritize features and ensure timely delivery.
- Troubleshooting issues as the first line of support.
- Gathering customer and user feedback to inform product requirements.
- Technical Support for US customers and L2 level support for EU traffic project.
- Understanding customer needs and behaviors through research and engagement.
- Developing and maintaining product documentation.

## EDUCATION AND TRAINING

12/06/2008 - 22/08/2012 India

**BTECH - INFORMATION TECHNOLOGY** Anna University

India

BUSINESS ANALYST TRAINING American Telephone And Telecommunication

SAP ABAP TRAINING Softech Bangalore

**PROJECT MANAGEMENT FOUNDATIONS** Linkedin

**DATA ANALYTICS ESSENTIAL CISCO** 

**ENGAGING STAKEHOLDERS FOR SUCCESS CISCO** 

#### DIGITAL SKILLS

IT Support and Technical Support. | Data Analysis, Visualization, Dashboard, Pivot, Reporting. | Supply Chain & Inventory software. | ASP .NET. | Crystal Report. | IIS | JSON | Qlik, Looker, Tableau and Power Bl. | Programming Languages: • C&C++ • C# • HTML | Databases: • SQL • MYSQL • Microsoft Access | Microsoft Office (Outlook, Excel, Word, PowerPoint) | JIRA | PowerShell | Project Management | API | Webhook | Postman

#### HONOURS AND AWARDS

31/12/2021

Outstanding Achievement Award 2021 – ALESSA – ALESSA

WES Degree certificate - WES.

04/02/2024

Model Employee Award - J&T Express - J&T Express KSA

# LANGUAGES KNOWN

English, Malayalam, Hindi, Tamil, Arabic and German